Chin Jie Ming

jameschin0531@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Hi, my name is James, I am a fullstack developer that has 3 years experience since 2019. I have been involved in 6 different projects and played different roles on the team. My current tech stack is using laravel, vue js and reactjs for web development, react native for mobile development but I am open to learn new skills and techstack to keep improving my skill sets.

My goal is to provide the biggest value to an organization or client to make their product successful in the market or transform their business from offline to online to increase their revenue with the latest technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SPARKSOFT SDN BHD - (Full Stack Engineer)

Jun 2019 – Feb 2023

A startup company that is headquartered in Malaysia. It is a company that is transforming the software development and digital marketing landscape. Sparksoft mainly offered clients digital marketing services with their own invented system.

Responsibilities:

- Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Develops software solutions by studying information needs, conferring with users, and studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes.
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Develop new user-facing features.
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders.
- Developing features to enhance the user experience.

1. Membership Suite - https://www.membershipsuite.app (2022-2023)

Membership Suite is an all in one membership management software that is able to eliminate repetitive manual tasks with easy-to-use automation and increase member retention.

- Revamp the back office web application interface
- Provide tech solution and implement it independently for new requirements
- Responsible to compile and submit the app to all app store platform
- Building interface and Restful API by using Vuejs and Laravel

2. Fightzone Singapore (2020-2023)

Fightzone is a gym management system that includes back office web application, trainer and sales application, and client application.

- Developed back office application using VueJS
- Doing the core module of the project for back office application (franchise management, lead/ client management, program management, schedule management, transaction management)
- Building base structure for the project (file structure, sharing CSS, global handling of API calling)
- Fixing any website issues or bugs that arise

3. 5Goal Project (2021)

- Doing two set of UI for webview and also mobile view
- Dealing with data provider vendor (Feijing) to ensure the required data is provided.
- Writing Go Script to crawl vendor data to our database.
- Doing the team and match module for the website.

4. ZHUI Project (2021)

- Work closely with team members by using react native.
- Create reusable components for team usage.
- Handle complex algorithms for different conditions that are used in the app.

5. TA Apps (2020)

Temperature Attendance is for users to record their temperature by uploading their temperature image to the app. Users can open groups and they will see their member temperature too.

- Work closely with team members by using react native.
- Develop the user interface using react-native element UI framework.
- Using redux to do global state management.
- Deployed the application to IOS and Android with my team.

6. LUCA project (2019-2020)

Luca has been developed as a potential marketing advertising channel for brands and individuals. Members using the app will get rewards by completing missions distributed by the merchant.

- Developed HCY merchant web and back office application using VueJS and NuxtJS framework.
- Work closely with the backed team to integrate Restful API for web application.
- Work closely with the design team and stakeholders in order to meet all business requirements and provide a good user experience interface.
- Using Puppeteer to scrape data from Facebook for the mission verification process.

BRIDZIA SDN BHD

Bridzia utilizes custom services tailor-made for client business and transforms the power of technology into a usable methodology for retaining sales and leads.

Responsibilities:

- Create and Customize Magento 2 module
- Fix website responsive problem on mobile devices
- Developed Website using Jquery, HTML and CSS

SKILL SETS

Programming languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP (Laravel)

Javascript Framework: Vue, React

CSS Framework: Vuetify, Bootstrap

Database: MySQL Firebase

Backend Knowledge: Cron Job, API, MVC, 2FA, Integrate Third Party Service

Server Knowledge: Linux (ubuntu/centos), FTP / SSH, Server Firewall, AWS

App Development: React Native, listing app on play store / app store / huawei store

Web Development: Wordpress, Hosting, Domain, SEO, Google Analytics, Google Search Console

Automation: Puppeteer

QUALIFICATIONS

ASIA PACIFIC UNIVERSITY

Bsc (Hons) in IT With Specialism In Mobile Technology (CGPA3.23)

Y2017-Y2019

Diploma in Information & Communication Technology (CGPA3.45)

Y2015-Y2017